Guide to the New York City COVID-19 Web Activism Collection TAM.798
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Coronavirus NYC Neighborhood Food Resource Guides, May 2020-ongoing; Hunter College. New York City Food Policy Center (Box Electronic Records)
  The Coronavirus NYC Neighborhood Food Resource Guide was developed by the Hunter College New York City Food Policy Center in order to "help community members in need with food resources during this challenging time." The website provides links to neighborhood specific guides for free or reduced-cost food programs, meals for students and seniors, meal delivery programs, and resources for immigrants across 59 neighborhoods in each of the five boroughs of New York City (Bronx, Brooklyn, Queens, Staten Island, and Manhattan).
- Teamsters Joint Council 16 Facebook, January-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
  Teamsters Joint Council 16 represents 120,000 workers in Downstate New York and Puerto Rico. Joint Council 16 represents workers in a wide range of industries inclusive of horse carriage drivers, truck drivers, public housing workers, airline staff, newspaper printers, film industry workers, manufacturers, construction workers, grocery workers and others. During COVID-19, many Teamsters were designated as "essential workers." In January of 2020, over 1,400 essential workers at Hunts Point Produce Market — the largest wholesale produce market in the country — launched a historic, week-long strike. Facing freezing weather and police brutality, the workers refused to concede their demand of Hunts Point Produce Market to raise hourly wage by $1-per-hour. On January 23rd, workers voted to end their strike after approving a new contract that includes a $1.85 wage increase over three years and ends out-of-pocket payments for family healthcare plans. The Teamsters Joint Council 16 Facebook account provides a visual record of the on-the-ground struggle of the strike.
- Teamsters Joint Council 16 Twitter, January 2021-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
  Teamsters Joint Council 16 represents 120,000 workers in Downstate New York and Puerto Rico. Joint Council 16 represents workers in a wide range of industries inclusive of horse carriage drivers, truck drivers, public housing workers, airline staff, newspaper printers, film industry workers, manufacturers, construction workers, grocery workers and others. During COVID-19, many Teamsters were designated as "essential workers." In January of 2020, over 1,400 essential workers at Hunts Point Produce Market — the largest wholesale produce market in the country — launched a historic, week-long strike. Facing freezing weather and police brutality, the workers refused to concede their demand of Hunts Point Produce Market to raise hourly wage by $1-per-hour. On January 23rd, workers voted to end their strike after approving a new contract that includes a $1.85 wage increase over three years and ends out-of-pocket payments for family healthcare plans. The Teamsters Joint Council 16 Twitter account documents the on-the-ground struggle of the strike, inclusive of short spotlight interviews, photographs, and videos (inclusive of Congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez joining the picket line).
- Teamsters NYC, January 2021-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
  Teamsters Joint Council 16 represents 120,000 workers in Downstate New York and Puerto Rico. Joint Council 16 represents workers in a wide range of industries inclusive of horse carriage drivers, truck drivers, public housing workers, airline staff, newspaper printers, film industry workers, manufacturers, construction workers, grocery workers and others. During COVID-19, many Teamsters were designated as "essential workers." In January of 2020, over 1,400 essential workers at Hunts Point Produce Market — the largest wholesale produce market in the country — launched a historic, week-long strike. Facing freezing weather and police brutality, the workers refused to concede their demand of Hunts Point Produce Market to raise hourly wage by $1-per-hour. On January 23rd, workers voted to end their strike after approving a new contract that includes a $1.85 wage increase over three years and ends out-of-pocket payments for family healthcare plans. The Teamsters website chronicles this effort in a series of news articles. The strike is further contextualized within the pandemic era through a COVID-19 memorial and a campaign page dedicated to the strike.
- Teamsters NYC COVID-19 Rights, January-March 2021; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
  eamsters Joint Council 16 represents 120,000 workers in Downstate New York and Puerto Rico. Joint Council 16 represents workers in a wide range of industries inclusive of horse carriage drivers, truck drivers, public housing workers, airline staff, newspaper printers, film industry workers, manufacturers, construction workers, grocery workers and others. This page contains information on workers rights during the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Teamsters NYC Hunts Point Strike, January 2021-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
- Teamsters NYC In Memoriam: Teamsters Lost to COVID-19, January 2021-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
- Justice Committee COVID Cop Watch, June 2020-ongoing; Justice Committee (Box Electronic Records)
  The Justice Committee (JC) is a grassroots organization dedicated to building a movement against police violence and systemic racism in New York City and empowering low-income Latino/as and other people of color to address these issues. By building solidarity with other anti-racist, immigrant and people of color-led organizations, they seek to contribute to a broad-based movement for social justice. JC also seeks to contribute to a coordinated global movement that will attain this world by building a New York City in which people are not victimized by systemic racism and other forms of oppression and do not suffer or fear killings and abuse at the hands of the NYPD and other forms of law enforcement.
- COVID-19: Sex Worker Harm Reduction Resources, June 2020-January 2021; Krongelb, Malana (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page highlighting physical and mental health, online work, and financial resources for sex workers.
- Tre Kwon Twitter, May 2020-ongoing; Kwon, Tre (Box Electronic Records)
  Tre Kwon is a writer and editor for Left Voice. She is a Mount Sinai ICU nurse and a member of NYSNA. Kwon joined other activists and workers in several different actions to demand more PPE and to denounce the conditions faced by frontline workers during the COVID-19 crisis. The mother of a newborn, her work and activism has been covered in mainstream and progressive/left news outlets such as BBC, CBS, Democracy Now, and The Intercept. Her tweets related to the struggles of healthcare workers during COVID-19 begin April 3, 2020 and include still and moving image documents and links to media outlets' reporting of healthcare workers during COVID-19
- Make The Road: Our COVID Response, May 2020-ongoing; Make the Road (New York) (Box Electronic Records)
  Make the Road New York is a grassroots immigrant and workers organization. They focus on education equity; health justice; housing and environmental justice; policing and criminal justice; transgender, gender non-conforming, intersex, and queer justice; and workplace justice. During the COVID-19 pandemic, they established an emergency response fund; held know your rights trainings; promoted advocacy campaigns related to an eviction moratorium and immigration enforcement; workers rights resources related to safety, paid sick leave, and unemployment; immigrant rights resources; the Emergency Rental Assistance program; and health and food program resources.
- Immigrant Accompaniment Networks & COVID-19, June 2020-February 2022; Metrowest Worker Center (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page related to immigrant justice; racism and COVID-19; immigration court; COVID vulnerability in immigration detention centers and prisons and jails; and protest information.
- MORE Caucus NYC, May 2020-March 2021; Movement of Rank and File Educators (Box Electronic Records)
  Movement of Rank and File Educators (MORE) is the social justice caucus of United Federation of Teachers (UFT) in New York City. The are an opposition group that offers themselves as a positive alternative to current union leadership. On April 8, 2020, MORE posted an open letter to Chancellor Carranza, Mayor De Blasio, and NYSED Interim Commissioner Shannon Tahoe proposing amendments to the City's emergency remote-learning plan for New York City Department of Education educators during the COVID-19 crisis. The letter calls for a slowdown in academics, a focus on trauma informed teaching, a suspension on grading for June report cards, support for the retention of a spring break, and more resources for public health initiatives.
- Mutual Aid NYC, May 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
  Mutual Aid NYC is a network of groups organizing to provide aid and support in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic. They are everyday New Yorkers working to lift up local organizing, connect people to resources, and build a citywide movement to address this crisis. Their members include parents, elders, immigrants, people with disabilities and chronic illness, caregivers, care workers, and other organizers. The page is fairly straightforward, with no AV. Most of the updates appear to be in the For Groups+ Organizers section, specifically the Find Resources + other groups page and the Case Studies page. Other sections include tips on using various social media platforms and collaborative tools and forms to request aid and to become a volunteer and donate to mutual aid groups.
- Mutual Aid NYC Community Resource Library, July 2021-ongoing; Mutual Aid NYC (Box Electronic Records)
  Resource library of New York City organization and programs developed by Mutual Aid NYC. The website is broken down into the following resource categories: Education, Housing, Money, Food, and Legal. It provides the name of the resource, the organization responsible for the resource, the website of the resource, contact information, location, and a description of the resource.
- Mutual Aid NYC Newsletter, July 2020-ongoing; Mutual Aid NYC (Box Electronic Records)
  A newsletter about mutual aid efforts around New York City by and for Mutual Aid NYC volunteers.
- COVID-19 Guidance for People Who Use Drugs and Harm Reduction Programs, May 2020-March 2021; National Harm Reduction Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  Harm Reduction Coalition is a bi-coastal network committed to drug user rights and overdose prevention. They aim to "challenge the persistent stigma faced by people who use drugs and advocate for policy and public health reform." The Harm Reduction Coalition's "COVID-19 Guidance for People Who Use Drugs" offers guides for safer drug use and harm reduction during the COVID-19 crisis. It also provides tips for community-based syringe services and need exchange providers. Guides are offered as links to PDF documents and are available in Portuguese, Arabic, and English.
- New York City COVID-19 Action, May 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  This website is compiled by grassroots organizers based in New York City and serves to support and amplify local campaigns by issue areas so that anyone can find a campaign and get involved immediately. The site includes sections on healthcare, housing, prison abolition, debt relief, utilities, immigration, labor, and environmental justice. Each section includes several links to petitions, google documents, call scripts, and links to relief funds related to COVID-19.
- New York Immigration Coalition List: NYC COVID-19 Resources & Services, May 2020-ongoing; New York Immigration Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  Google sheet with COVID-19 resources and services compiled by the New York Immigration Coalition (NYIC). The spreadsheet is organized by FAQs, education, employment, finances, food, health care, and small business.
- New York Immigration Coalition-COVID-19 Resources, May 2020-ongoing; New York Immigration Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  The New York Immigration Coalition (NYIC) is a policy and advocacy umbrella organization that represents immigrant and refugee rights groups across New York. Membership in NYIC is inclusive of labor unions, academic institutions, religious groups, legal organizations, and socio economic justice organizations. The NYIC COVID-19 Resources websites provides links to one-page PDF briefs with information on how COVID-19 affects health, education, immigration, social services, and civic engagement in New York. Documentation is translated into eight languages inclusive of Spanish, Arabic, Bengali, Korean, Chinese, Haitian Creole, Russian, and English. The website also provides links to PDF community toolkits that share know-your-rights information, food bank information, mental health and domestic violence resources, and information on reporting hate crimes.The website also offers links to PDFs describing access to COVID-19 testing, evaluation, and treatment services covered by Medicaid.
- New York Immigration Coalition: NYC COVID-19 Resources & Services, October 2020-ongoing; New York Immigration Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
- Take Action to Support All New Yorkers, May 2020-February 2022; New York Immigration Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  Petition put together by the New York Immigration Coalition to support the New York United campaign to ensure immigrants in New York State remain healthy and safe during the COVID-19 pandemic.
- New York State Nurses Association COVID-19 Resources, May 2020-ongoing; New York State Nurses Association (Box Electronic Records)
  The New York State Nurses Association is a union of 42,000 frontline nurses. They are New York's largest union and professional association for registered nurses. Their COVID-19 Resources page has daily updates that include tributes to nurses who were victims of COVID-19, forms for nurses who want to protest their assignment, FAQs related to sick leave and testing safety, and preparedness checklists, vaccine and booster information, COVID variants, mask guidance, and safe staffing. The page also encourages nurses to participate in a daily diary project, and several links to petitions.
- President Trump: Use the Defense Production Act to get frontline healthcare workers armor in the battle against COVID-19 Petition, May 2020-February 2022; New York State Nurses Association (Box Electronic Records)
  Petition compiled by New York State Nurses Association on increasing supply of personal protection equipment.
- Tell Governor Cuomo: Implement NYSNA's COVID-19 Surge Action Plan! Petition, May 2020-February 2022; New York State Nurses Association (Box Electronic Records)
  Petition compiled by New York State Nurses Association on creating a COVID-19 surge action plan.
- #NoBodyIsDisposable Know Your Rights Guide to Surviving COVID-19 Triage Protocols, June 2020-February 2022; NoBody Is Disposable Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page. Toolkit for people facing potential COVID-19 triage discrimination based on disability or weight.
- NYC COVID Care, June 2020-April 2022; NYC Covid Care Network (Box Electronic Records)
  NYC COVID Care is a mutual aid network comprised of therapists, psychiatrists, counselors, life coaches, grief counselors, spiritual care providers, organizers, and crisis line workers. They focus on facilitating individual support encounters, support groups, stress-reduction trainings, and grief and loss rituals. All individual support meetings happen by video or telephone. They make it clear that they are not offering therapy, but are connecting individuals for care and support. Some of the individuals involved in the project are licensed therapists, professionally certified to offer therapeutic services. As consenting adults, participants are encouraged to construct the relationship that feels most helpful. Once they connect individuals, the interaction is outside the network.
- NYC United Against Coronavirus, May-November 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
  NYC United Against Coronavirus is run by a group of volunteers who have set up a Google Doc, an email address, a Twitter account, an Instagram, and a Facebook page. The Google Doc provides a fairly comprehensive list of mutual aid actions and organizations across NYC. Sections include Immediate Needs (pg. 2-18), Get Organized, Advocacy, Local Information, and Other Resources. The list also includes links to the list in other languages (Spanish, Mandarin, Korean, with more languages coming soon). The doc is mostly made up of links to different forms, websites, social media accounts, and email addresses.
- NYC United Against Coronavirus, November 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYC Veterans Alliance, June 2020-February 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
  NYC Veterans Alliance exists to "empower veterans, families, and civilian allies to connect as a community, advocate for improved policies, and advance as civic leaders." Beginning in mid-March 2020, NYC Veterans Alliance started the Veterans Mutual Aid project to support veterans and their families with facing the realities of the pandemic, from housing insecurity to food scarcity. The Veterans Mutual Aid project includes information on tenants rights, workers rights, food and financial assistance, and support for veterans benefits claims during COVID-19. It also provides links to mental health assistance and ways to support others and stay connected during the crisis.
- Half Assed Disabled Prepper Tips for Preparing for a Coronavirus Quarantine, June 2020-February 2022; Piepzna-Samarasinha, Leah Lakshmi, 1975- (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page. Toolkit for disabled people to prepare for COVID-19 quarantine.
- Utilities Strike Toolkit, May 2020-February 2022; Public Power Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  Toolkit linked from the New York City COVID-19 Action campaign list. The toolkit calls for a strike of utility bills during the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Queens Neighborhoods United Instagram, May 2020-ongoing; Queens Neighborhoods United (Box Electronic Records)
  Queens Neighborhood United (QNU) is a volunteer, activist working group representing the neighborhoods of Jackson Heights, Corona, and Elmhurst. Founded in 2014 by small business owners as an anti-business improvement district organization, QNU "believes in establishing community control over land-use, policing, and immigration policies that directly impact and works to displace us." It accomplishes its work through use of grassroots organizing, direct action, leadership development, advocacy, and community education. Beginning on April 1, 2020, QNU uses its Instagram account to communicate directly to its members and allies around campaigns to support its community during COVID-19. The feed includes still and moving image and calls for support for Elmhurst Hospital, emergency response funds for laundry workers, announcements for know your rights trainings, and actions to support houseless community members. The un-archived Instagram feed includes video of an NYPD arrest of a houseless immigrant man which has not been included in this web archive in accordance with this collection's development policy and in order to preserve that individual's privacy
- Organizing Toolkit - Rent Strike 2020, June 2020-February 2022; Rent Strike 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page. The document calls for a freeze of rent, utilities and mortgage payments; freeze of student, consumer, and medical debt; tax of big business; housing for all unsheltered people; as well as other demands and how to orgainze around the demands.
- Evictions Protections during COVID: Know Your Rights, February 2022-ongoing; Right to Counsel NYC Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  An FAQ created by the Right to Counsel NYC Coalition that explained the New York eviction moratorium under the Tenant Safe Hard Act that was established from March 7, 2020 to January 15, 2022 if the tenant suffered financial hardship due to COVID-19. Also discusses other resources and protections for tenants.
- New York Tenants: Eviction Protections, The Courts, New & Pending Eviction Cases, February 2022-ongoing; Right to Counsel NYC Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document breakdown the executive orders, court directives, and new laws related to evictions, new case filings, and court closures during COVID-19.
- Sex Workers Outreach Project Brooklyn, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
  Sex Workers Outreach Project (SWOP) is a "peer-led organization supporting and advocating for sex workers in New York." In response to COVID-19 SWOP Brooklyn created a campaign "to provide monetary aid to sex workers in the New York City area who are in critical need of aid." The SWOP Brooklyn COVID web page offers guides and resources to support sex workers during the pandemic, and the SWOP Brooklyn homepage provides regularly updated data on how their funding is being allocated -- largely to individual stipends, but also to outreach and housing for individuals being released from Rikers.
- Accessible Remedials During COVID-19, June 2020-February 2022; Sex Workers Outreach Project Brooklyn (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document detailing accessible remedials for COVID-19 and pneumonia/bronchial infections.
- Chris Smalls (Amazon Strike) Instagram, May 2020-ongoing; Smalls, Chris (Box Electronic Records)
  Christian "Chris" Smalls, a management assistant at Amazon Warehouse JFK98 located on Staten Island, was fired by Amazon on March 30th, 2020 after organizing a strike to call attention to the lack of protections for workers at the facility. Documentation of Smalls' labor and COVID-19 activism begins with a March 30th, 2020 post in which Smalls includes images of the Amazon walkout and a quote from an interview with Smalls in Jacobin magazine. Smalls' Instagram feed includes still image and video posts documenting the walkout, artwork depicting Smalls, calls for action, fundraising campaigns related to supporting striking Amazon workers, and social justice focused events and programming in which Smalls is a participant.
- Christian Smalls Twitter, May 2020-ongoing; Smalls, Chris (Box Electronic Records)